Carlos Gatti

Dorchester, Massachusetts, United States



eduardo.gf@hotmail.com



+1 (857) 350-7504



linkedin.com/in/carlos-gatti-693b909b

Summary

I am a full stack developer with a passion for building and designing creative, responsive, web applications. Experience in building full-stack applications using JavaScript, TypeScript, React/Redux, CSS, NodeJs and NextJs as well as experience in backend development. I am a lifelong student of digital art, design, and technology. I focus on improving my work in and out of formal educational environments.

Experience



Full Stack Developer

CSA-Gatti

Jan 2015 - Present (7 years 2 months +)

CSA is a technology company located in Brazil. It is a company built to serve other companies that need to develop technologically.

At CSA I work as a programmer and I am also responsible for managing your finances.

The objective of this company is to build standards for processes in a scalable way, where development accompanies growth.

Some achievements during this period:

- Development of micro-services to serve the different customers and their applications;
- Development of robots for process automation and analysis in the financial market;
- Construction of dashboard for customers;
- Websites Develop and maintain commercials;
- Development of graphic indicators for the FOREX market;

Technologies:

Python

Node

React

GraphQL

Mysql

AWS

Google Cloud

VVALE HR Analyst PI - Full Stack Developer

Vale

Oct 2017 - Mar 2018 (6 months)

Vale is a global mining company, transforming natural resources into prosperity and sustainable development. Headquartered in Brazil and present in about 30 countries, it has approximately 125,000 people including direct employees and permanent contractors.

At Vale I worked with a human resources team to help create solutions that fill gaps in the department's workflow.

The focus was on facilitating the indicators for the entire Board and their levels, cooperating for a better workflow for users and finding ways to provide functionality or data they need for the routine of their work.

Some achievements of this period:

- Every year I was evaluated with high performance. This evaluation was carried out by recommendations from coworkers and by an evaluation of all managers in the department.
- Reconstructed and maintained a platform that we call the HR Portal. The development technical front-end and back-end was done entirely by me. Being a support base for various indicators and processes, such as: termination interview and monitoring of salary movements.
- Developed a service panel responsible for directing calls from people who needed a service in the HR department. Categorizing in indicators as main occurrences of service by department, making it possible to work preventively.
- I built a web application responsible for registering and updating the status of a super important process for employees when it comes to retirement. This application worked throughout the Brazil and some locations in Africa.
- I also contributed to the development of smaller tools such as direct mail for communication, development of support worksheets and others.

Technologies:

React

C#

Javascript

Angular

VBA

Azure

Mvsal

Power BI

Azure Cloud

The reason for the termination request was that my family and I decided to move to another country in order to develop a second language.

YALE HR Analyst Jr - Full Stack Developer

Vale

Sep 2011 - Sep 2017 (6 years 1 month)

During this period I had the opportunity to build a web application to facilitate the management of the retirement process for all employees of the Vale group in Brazil and other countries. Before this integration, the process was controlled by each region. This resulted in a long and complicated process. Which made me visualize an opportunity for improvement.

My idea was to build a web application containing a standard form to monitor the progress of the process. In this way all human resources analysts would have access to generate management reports and also track demands more easily. This also provided greater speed in the information and as a consequence of this a greater speed in the delivery of documents.

Some of my main activities in this period were:

- Raise all technical requirements with the HR and IT team;
- Construction of a relational database to store project data in test and production environment, involving diagram modeling;
- Develop screen mockups to demonstrate user experience;
- Develop an API in NodeJs to provide endpoints;
- Develop a frontend using javascript tools;
- Build test environment;
- Build deployment and production environment;
- Platform access and security management.

The biggest challenge in that period was the initial phase as we had to migrate the existing information in spreadsheets. However, the team really engaged with the idea making it a success.

With this project I had the opportunity to be better known and recognized within the company as the project became a reference throughout the company.

After the stabilization of the system and the creation of focal points training to the users all the process became simpler. So, I was relocated to a human resources innovation department.

Education



👩 Universidade Vila Velha - UVV

Bachelor's degree, Information Technology 2016 - 2020



🔕 Universidade Vila Velha - UVV

Bachelor's degree, Engineering 2008 - 2015

Licenses & Certifications

Hx edX Verified Certificate for Data Science: Probability - HarvardX d928b0148c7c404c9acb50af13413d7b

Scrum: Agility in your project - Alura

- Node.js: Innovating with Javascript in the backend Alura 4adbb334-72b9-4df6-a997-2138192c7d97
- MySQL I: Starting your queries Alura 2917c12851e23708da7ab1abc9cfe2f9
- MySQL II: Powerful queries Alura cbbd5b67b58b9a969808049d94cd7033
- Relational Database Modeling: Indexes and Normalization Alura e5b73bc9-49d9-4c4a-9c52-ae83b976ed02
- JavaScript: Programming in web language Alura 51f8b8825d6f47b2ab056c9b53c8fd22
- JavaScript Expert Alura ea9b2673-46dd-4111-bcd4-9536d11bf027
- Node.js e HTTP: developing an API following the REST style Alura caabcceb-f1e2-4987-a3c0-f026e6b739da

Skills

Node.js • React.js • JavaScript • Data Science • Scrum • Python (Programming Language) • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Google Cloud Platform (GCP) • MySQL • Git